table	column	label	description
SF1	revenue	Revenues	[Income Statement] The amount of Revenue recognised from goods sold; services rendered; insurance premiums; or other activities that constitute an earning process. Interest income for financial institutions is reported net of interest expense and provision for credit losses. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	cor	Cost of Revenue	[Income Statement] The aggregate cost of goods produced and sold and services rendered during the reporting period. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	sgna	Selling General and Administrative Expense	[Income Statement] A component of [OpEx] representing the aggregate total costs related to selling a firm's product and services; as well as all other general and administrative expenses. Direct selling expenses (for example; credit; warranty; and advertising) are expenses that can be directly linked to the sale of specific products. Indirect selling expenses are expenses that cannot be directly linked to the sale of specific products; for example telephone expenses; Internet; and postal charges. General and administrative expenses include salaries of non-sales personnel; rent; utilities; communication; etc. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	rnd	Research and Development Expense	[Income Statement] A component of [OpEx] representing the aggregate costs incurred in a planned search or critical investigation aimed at discovery of new knowledge with the hope that such knowledge will be useful in developing a new product or service. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	opex	Operating Expenses	[Income Statement] Operating expenses represent the total expenditure on [SGnA]; [RnD] and other operating expense items; it excludes [CoR].
SF1	intexp	Interest Expense	[Income Statement] Amount of the cost of borrowed funds accounted for as interest expense. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	taxexp	Income Tax Expense	[Income Statement] Amount of current income tax expense (benefit) and deferred income tax expense (benefit) pertaining to continuing operations. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	netincdis	Net Loss Income from Discontinued Operations	[Income Statement] Amount of loss (income) from a disposal group; net of income tax; reported as a separate component of income. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	consolinc	Consolidated Income	[Income Statement] The portion of profit or loss for the period; net of income taxes; which is attributable to the consolidated entity; before the deduction of [NetIncNCI].
SF1	netincnci	Net Income to Non-Controlling Interests	[Income Statement] The portion of income which is attributable to non-controlling interest shareholders; subtracted from [ConsolInc] in order to obtain [NetInc]. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	netinc	Net Income	[Income Statement] The portion of profit or loss for the period; net of income taxes; which is attributable to the parent after the deduction of [NetIncNCI] from [ConsolInc]; and before the deduction of [PrefDivIS].
SF1	prefdivis	Preferred Dividends Income Statement Impact	[Income Statement] Income statement item reflecting dividend payments to preferred stockholders. Subtracted from Net Income to Parent [NetInc] to obtain Net Income to Common Stockholders [NetIncCmn]. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	netinccmn	Net Income Common Stock	[Income Statement] The amount of net income (loss) for the period due to common shareholders. Typically differs from [NetInc] to the parent entity due to the deduction of [PrefDivIS].
SF1	eps	Earnings per Basic Share	[Income Statement] Earnings per share as calculated and reported by the company. Approximates to the amount of [NetIncCmn] for the period per each [SharesWA] after adjusting for [ShareFactor].
SF1	epsdil	Earnings per Diluted Share	[Income Statement] Earnings per diluted share as calculated and reported by the company. Approximates to the amount of [NetIncCmn] for the period per each [SharesWADil] after adjusting for [ShareFactor]..
SF1	shareswa	Weighted Average Shares	[Income Statement] The weighted average number of shares or units issued and outstanding that are used by the company to calculate [EPS]; determined based on the timing of issuance of shares or units in the period.
SF1	shareswadil	Weighted Average Shares Diluted	[Income Statement] The weighted average number of shares or units issued and outstanding that are used by the company to calculate [EPSDil]; determined based on the timing of issuance of shares or units in the period.
SF1	capex	Capital Expenditure	[Cash Flow Statement] A component of [NCFI] representing the net cash inflow (outflow) associated with the acquisition & disposal of long-lived; physical & intangible assets that are used in the normal conduct of business to produce goods and services and are not intended for resale. Includes cash inflows/outflows to pay for construction of self-constructed assets & software. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	ncfbus	Net Cash Flow - Business Acquisitions and Disposals	[Cash Flow Statement] A component of [NCFI] representing the net cash inflow (outflow) associated with the acquisition & disposal of businesses; joint-ventures; affiliates; and other named investments. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	ncfinv	Net Cash Flow - Investment Acquisitions and Disposals	[Cash Flow Statement] A component of [NCFI] representing the net cash inflow (outflow) associated with the acquisition & disposal of investments; including marketable securities and loan originations. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	fcfps	Free Cash Flow per Share	[Metrics] Free Cash Flow per Share is a valuation metric calculated by dividing [FCF] by [SharesWA] and [ShareFactor].
SF1	ncff	Net Cash Flow from Financing	[Cash Flow Statement] A component of [NCF] representing the amount of cash inflow (outflow) from financing activities; from continuing and discontinued operations. Principal components of financing cash flow are: issuance (purchase) of equity shares; issuance (repayment) of debt securities; and payment of dividends & other cash distributions. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	ncfdebt	Issuance (Repayment) of Debt Securities 	[Cash Flow Statement] A component of [NCFF] representing the net cash inflow (outflow) from issuance (repayment) of debt securities. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	ncfcommon	Issuance (Purchase) of Equity Shares	[Cash Flow Statement] A component of [NCFF] representing the net cash inflow (outflow) from common equity changes. Includes additional capital contributions from share issuances and exercise of stock options; and outflow from share repurchases.  Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	ncfdiv	Payment of Dividends & Other Cash Distributions   	[Cash Flow Statement] A component of [NCFF] representing dividends and dividend equivalents paid on common stock and restricted stock units. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	ncfi	Net Cash Flow from Investing	[Cash Flow Statement] A component of [NCF] representing the amount of cash inflow (outflow) from investing activities; from continuing and discontinued operations. Principal components of investing cash flow are: capital (expenditure) disposal of equipment [CapEx]; business (acquisitions) disposition [NCFBus] and investment (acquisition) disposal [NCFInv]. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	ncfo	Net Cash Flow from Operations	[Cash Flow Statement] A component of [NCF] representing the amount of cash inflow (outflow) from operating activities; from continuing and discontinued operations.
SF1	ncfx	Effect of Exchange Rate Changes on Cash 	[Cash Flow Statement] A component of Net Cash Flow [NCF] representing the amount of increase (decrease) from the effect of exchange rate changes on cash and cash equivalent balances held in foreign currencies. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	ncf	Net Cash Flow / Change in Cash & Cash Equivalents	[Cash Flow Statement] Principal component of the cash flow statement representing the amount of increase (decrease) in cash and cash equivalents. Includes [NCFO]; investing [NCFI] and financing [NCFF] for continuing and discontinued operations; and the effect of exchange rate changes on cash [NCFX].
SF1	sbcomp	Share Based Compensation	[Cash Flow Statement] A component of [NCFO] representing the total amount of noncash; equity-based employee remuneration. This may include the value of stock or unit options; amortization of restricted stock or units; and adjustment for officers' compensation. As noncash; this element is an add back when calculating net cash generated by operating activities using the indirect method.
SF1	depamor	Depreciation Amortization & Accretion	[Cash Flow Statement] A component of operating cash flow representing the aggregate net amount of depreciation; amortization; and accretion recognized during an accounting period. As a non-cash item; the net amount is added back to net income when calculating cash provided by or used in operations using the indirect method. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	assets	Total Assets	[Balance Sheet] Sum of the carrying amounts as of the balance sheet date of all assets that are recognized. Major components are [CashnEq]; [Investments];[Intangibles]; [PPNENet];[TaxAssets] and [Receivables].
SF1	cashneq	Cash and Equivalents	[Balance Sheet] A component of [Assets] representing the amount of currency on hand as well as demand deposits with banks or financial institutions. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	investments	Investments	[Balance Sheet] A component of [Assets] representing the total amount of marketable and non-marketable securties; loans receivable and other invested assets. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	investmentsc	Investments Current	[Balance Sheet] The current portion of [Investments]; reported if the company operates a classified balance sheet that segments current and non-current assets. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	investmentsnc	Investments Non-Current	[Balance Sheet] The non-current portion of [Investments]; reported if the company operates a classified balance sheet that segments current and non-current assets. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	deferredrev	Deferred Revenue	[Balance Sheet] A component of [Liabilities] representing the carrying amount of consideration received or receivable on potential earnings that were not recognized as revenue; including sales; license fees; and royalties; but excluding interest income. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	deposits	Deposit Liabilities	[Balance Sheet] A component of [Liabilities] representing the total of all deposit liabilities held; including foreign and domestic; interest and noninterest bearing. May include demand deposits; saving deposits; Negotiable Order of Withdrawal and time deposits among others. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	ppnenet	Property Plant & Equipment Net	[Balance Sheet] A component of [Assets] representing the amount after accumulated depreciation; depletion and amortization of physical assets used in the normal conduct of business to produce goods and services and not intended for resale. Includes Operating Right of Use Assets. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	inventory	Inventory	[Balance Sheet] A component of [Assets] representing the amount after valuation and reserves of inventory expected to be sold; or consumed within one year or operating cycle; if longer. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	taxassets	Tax Assets	[Balance Sheet] A component of [Assets] representing tax assets and receivables. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	receivables	Trade and Non-Trade Receivables	[Balance Sheet] A component of [Assets] representing trade and non-trade receivables. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	payables	Trade and Non-Trade Payables	[Balance Sheet] A component of [Liabilities] representing trade and non-trade payables. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	intangibles	Goodwill and Intangible Assets	[Balance Sheet] A component of [Assets] representing the carrying amounts of all intangible assets and goodwill as of the balance sheet date; net of accumulated amortization and impairment charges. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	liabilities	Total Liabilities	[Balance Sheet] Sum of the carrying amounts as of the balance sheet date of all liabilities that are recognized. Principal components are [Debt]; [DeferredRev]; [Payables];[Deposits]; and [TaxLiabilities].
SF1	equity	Shareholders Equity Attributable to Parent	[Balance Sheet] A principal component of the balance sheet; in addition to [Liabilities] and [Assets]; that represents the total of all stockholders' equity (deficit) items; net of receivables from officers; directors; owners; and affiliates of the entity which are attributable to the parent.
SF1	retearn	Accumulated Retained Earnings (Deficit)	[Balance Sheet] A component of [Equity] representing the cumulative amount of the entities undistributed earnings or deficit. May only be reported annually by certain companies; rather than quarterly.
SF1	accoci	Accumulated Other Comprehensive Income	[Balance Sheet] A component of [Equity] representing the accumulated change in equity from transactions and other events and circumstances from non-owner sources; net of tax effect; at period end. Includes foreign currency translation items; certain pension adjustments; unrealized gains and losses on certain investments in debt and equity securities. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	assetsc	Current Assets	[Balance Sheet] The current portion of [Assets]; reported if a company operates a classified balance sheet that segments current and non-current assets.
SF1	assetsnc	Assets Non-Current	[Balance Sheet] Amount of non-current assets; for companies that operate a classified balance sheet. Calculated as the different between Total Assets [Assets] and Current Assets [AssetsC].
SF1	liabilitiesc	Current Liabilities	[Balance Sheet] The current portion of [Liabilities]; reported if the company operates a classified balance sheet that segments current and non-current liabilities.
SF1	liabilitiesnc	Liabilities Non-Current	[Balance Sheet] The non-current portion of [Liabilities]; reported if the company operates a classified balance sheet that segments current and non-current liabilities.
SF1	taxliabilities	Tax Liabilities	[Balance Sheet] A component of [Liabilities] representing outstanding tax liabilities. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	debt	Total Debt	[Balance Sheet] A component of [Liabilities] representing the total amount of current and non-current debt owed. Includes secured and unsecured bonds issued; commercial paper; notes payable; credit facilities; lines of credit; capital lease obligations; operating lease obligations; and convertible notes. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	debtc	Debt Current	[Balance Sheet] The current portion of [Debt]; reported if the company operates a classified balance sheet that segments current and non-current liabilities. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	debtnc	Debt Non-Current	[Balance Sheet] The non-current portion of [Debt] reported if the company operates a classified balance sheet that segments current and non-current liabilities. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	ebt	Earnings before Tax	[Metrics] Earnings Before Tax is calculated by adding [TaxExp] back to [NetInc].
SF1	ebit	Earning Before Interest & Taxes (EBIT)	[Income Statement] Earnings Before Interest and Tax is calculated by adding [TaxExp] and [IntExp] back to [NetInc].
SF1	ebitda	Earnings Before Interest Taxes & Depreciation Amortization (EBITDA)	[Metrics] EBITDA is a non-GAAP accounting metric that is widely used when assessing the performance of companies; calculated by adding [DepAmor] back to [EBIT].
SF1	fxusd	Foreign Currency to USD Exchange Rate	[Metrics] The exchange rate used for the conversion of foreign currency to USD for non-US companies that do not report in USD.
SF1	equityusd	Shareholders Equity (USD)	[Balance Sheet] [Equity] in USD; converted by [FXUSD].
SF1	epsusd	Earnings per Basic Share (USD)	[Income Statement] [EPS] in USD; converted by [FXUSD].
SF1	revenueusd	Revenues (USD)	[Income Statement] [Revenue] in USD; converted by [FXUSD]. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	netinccmnusd	Net Income Common Stock (USD)	[Income Statement] [NetIncCmn] in USD; converted by [FXUSD].
SF1	cashnequsd	Cash and Equivalents (USD)	[Balance Sheet] [CashnEq] in USD; converted by [FXUSD]. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	bvps	Book Value per Share	[Metrics] Measures the ratio between [Equity] and [SharesWA] as adjusted by [ShareFactor].
SF1	debtusd	Total Debt (USD)	[Balance Sheet] [Debt] in USD; converted by [FXUSD]. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	ebitusd	Earning Before Interest & Taxes (USD)	[Income Statement] [EBIT] in USD; converted by [FXUSD].
SF1	ebitdausd	Earnings Before Interest Taxes & Depreciation Amortization (USD)	[Metrics] [EBITDA] in USD; converted by [FXUSD].
SF1	sharesbas	Shares (Basic)	[Entity] The number of shares or other units outstanding of the entity's capital or common stock or other ownership interests; as stated on the cover of related periodic report (10-K/10-Q); after adjustment for stock splits.
SF1	dps	Dividends per Basic Common Share	[Income Statement] Aggregate dividends declared during the period for each split-adjusted share of common stock outstanding. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	sharefactor	Share Factor	[Entity] Share factor is a multiplicand in the calculation of [MarketCap] and is used to adjust for: American Depository Receipts (ADRs) that represent more or less than 1 underlying share; and; companies which have different earnings share for different share classes (eg Berkshire Hathaway - BRK.B).
SF1	marketcap	Market Capitalization	[Metrics] Represents the product of [SharesBas]; [Price] and [ShareFactor].
SF1	ev	Enterprise Value	[Metrics] Enterprise value is a measure of the value of a business as a whole; calculated as [MarketCap] plus [DebtUSD] minus [CashnEqUSD].
SF1	invcap	Invested Capital	[Metrics] Invested capital is an input into the calculation of [ROIC]; and is calculated as: [Debt] plus [Assets] minus [Intangibles] minus [CashnEq] minus [LiabilitiesC]. Please note this calculation method is subject to change.
SF1	equityavg	Average Equity	[Metrics] Average equity value for the period used in calculation of [ROE]; derived from [Equity].
SF1	assetsavg	Average Assets	[Metrics] Average asset value for the period used in calculation of [ROE] and [ROA]; derived from [Assets].
SF1	invcapavg	Invested Capital Average	[Metrics] Average invested capital value for the period used in the calculation of [ROIC]; and derived from [InvCap]. Invested capital is an input into the calculation of [ROIC]; and is calculated as: [Debt] plus [Assets] minus [Intangibles] minus [CashnEq] minus [LiabilitiesC]. Please note this calculation method is subject to change.
SF1	tangibles	Tangible Asset Value	[Metrics] The value of tangibles assets calculated as the difference between [Assets] and [Intangibles].
SF1	roe	Return on Average Equity	[Metrics] Return on equity measures a corporation's profitability by calculating the amount of [NetIncCmn] returned as a percentage of [EquityAvg].
SF1	roa	Return on Average Assets	[Metrics] Return on assets measures how profitable a company is [NetIncCmn] relative to its total assets [AssetsAvg].
SF1	fcf	Free Cash Flow	[Metrics] Free Cash Flow is a measure of financial performance calculated as [NCFO] minus [CapEx].
SF1	roic	Return on Invested Capital	[Metrics] Return on Invested Capital is a ratio estimated by dividing [EBIT] by [InvCapAvg]. [InvCap] is calculated as: [Debt] plus [Assets] minus [Intangibles] minus [CashnEq] minus [LiabilitiesC]. Please note this calculation method is subject to change.
SF1	gp	Gross Profit	[Income Statement] Aggregate revenue [Revenue] less cost of revenue [CoR] directly attributable to the revenue generation activity.
SF1	opinc	Operating Income	[Income Statement] Operating income is a measure of financial performance before the deduction of [IntExp]; [TaxExp] and other Non-Operating items. It is calculated as [GP] minus [OpEx].
SF1	grossmargin	Gross Margin	[Metrics] Gross Margin measures the ratio between a company's [GP] and [Revenue].
SF1	netmargin	Profit Margin	[Metrics] Measures the ratio between a company's [NetIncCmn] and [Revenue].
SF1	ebitdamargin	EBITDA Margin	[Metrics] Measures the ratio between a company's [EBITDA] and [Revenue].
SF1	ros	Return on Sales	[Metrics] Return on Sales is a ratio to evaluate a company's operational efficiency; calculated by dividing [EBIT] by [Revenue]. ROS is often a component of DuPont ROE analysis.
SF1	assetturnover	Asset Turnover	[Metrics] Asset turnover is a measure of a firms operating efficiency; calculated by dividing [Revenue] by [AssetsAVG]. Often a component of DuPont ROE analysis.
SF1	payoutratio	Payout Ratio	[Metrics] The percentage of earnings paid as dividends to common stockholders. Calculated by dividing [DPS] by [EPSUSD].
SF1	evebitda	Enterprise Value over EBITDA	[Metrics] Measures the ratio between [EV] and [EBITDAUSD].
SF1	evebit	Enterprise Value over EBIT	[Metrics] Measures the ratio between [EV] and [EBITUSD].
SF1	pe	Price Earnings (Damodaran Method)	[Metrics] Measures the ratio between [MarketCap] and [NetIncCmnUSD]
SF1	pe1	Price to Earnings Ratio	[Metrics] An alternative to [PE] representing the ratio between [Price] and [EPSUSD].
SF1	sps	Sales per Share	[Metrics] Sales per Share measures the ratio between [RevenueUSD] and [SharesWA] as adjusted by [ShareFactor].
SF1	ps1	Price to Sales Ratio	[Metrics] An alternative calculation method to [PS]; that measures the ratio between a company's [Price] and it's [SPS].
SF1	ps	Price Sales (Damodaran Method)	[Metrics] Measures the ratio between [MarketCap] and [RevenueUSD].
SF1	pb	Price to Book Value	[Metrics] Measures the ratio between [MarketCap] and [EquityUSD].
SF1	de	Debt to Equity Ratio	[Metrics] Measures the ratio between [Liabilities] and [Equity].
SF1	divyield	Dividend Yield	[Metrics] Dividend Yield measures the ratio between a company's trailing twelve month [DPS] and its [Price]. Where this item is not contained on the company consolidated financial statements and cannot otherwise be imputed the value of 0 is used.
SF1	currentratio	Current Ratio	[Metrics] The ratio between [AssetsC] and [LiabilitiesC]; for companies that operate a classified balance sheet.
SF1	workingcapital	Working Capital	[Metrics] Working capital measures the difference between [AssetsC] and [LiabilitiesC].
SF1	tbvps	Tangible Assets Book Value per Share	[Metrics] Measures the ratio between [Tangibles] and [SharesWA] as adjusted by [ShareFactor].
SF1	price	Share Price (Adjusted Close)	[Entity] The price per common share adjusted for stock splits but not adjusted for dividends; used in the computation of [PE1]; [PS1]; [DivYield] and [SPS].
SF1	ticker	Ticker Symbol	[Entity] The ticker is a unique identifier for a security in the database. Where a company is delisted and the ticker subsequently recycled for use by a different company; we utilise that ticker for the currently active company and append a number to the ticker of the delisted company. The ACTIONS table provides a record of historical ticker changes.
SF1	dimension	Dimension	[Entity] The dimension field allows you to take different dimensional views of data over time. ARQ: Quarterly; excluding restatements; MRQ: Quarterly; including restatements; ARY: annual; excluding restatements; MRY: annual; including restatements; ART: trailing-twelve-months; excluding restatements; MRT: trailing-twelve-months; including restatements.
SF1	calendardate	Calendar Date	[Entity] The Calendar Date represents the normalized [ReportPeriod]. This provides a common date to query for which is necessary due to irregularity in report periods across companies. For example; if the report period is 2015-09-26; the calendar date will be 2015-09-30 for quarterly and trailing-twelve-month dimensions (ARQ;MRQ;ART;MRT); and 2015-12-31 for annual dimensions (ARY;MRY). We also employ offsets in order to maximise comparability of the period across companies. For example consider two companies: one with a quarter ending on 2018-07-24; and the other with a quarter ending on 2018-06-28. A naive normalization process would assign these to differing calendar quarters of 2018-09-30 and 2018-06-30 respectively. However; we assign these both to the 2018-06-30 calendar quarter because this maximises the overlap in the report periods in question and therefore the comparability of this period.
SF1	datekey	Date Key	[Entity] The Date Key represents the SEC filing date for AR dimensions (ARQ;ART;ARY); and the [REPORTPERIOD] for MR dimensions (MRQ;MRT;MRY). In addition; this is the observation date used for [Price] based data such as [MarketCap]; [Price] and [PE].
SF1	reportperiod	Report Period	[Entity] The Report Period represents the end date of the fiscal period.
SF1	lastupdated	Last Updated Date	[Entity] Last Updated represents the last date that this database entry was updated; which is useful to users when updating their local records.
SF1	fiscalperiod	Fiscal Period	The fiscal period of the report expressed as follows: 2024-Q2; 2024-Q3; 2024-FY etc. Note that companies can have different fiscal periods for the report period due to different year end dates.
SF2	ticker	Ticker Symbol	The ticker is a unique identifier for a security in the database. Where a company is delisted and the ticker subsequently recycled for use by a different company; we utilise that ticker for the currently active company and append a number to the ticker of the delisted company. The ACTIONS table provides a record of historical ticker changes.
SF2	filingdate	Filing Date	The date the form was filed with the SEC.
SF2	formtype	Form Type	The type of SEC form . Available options are 3; 4 or 5 that the data are sourced from. Preprended by RESTATED in the event that the filing is subsequently restated.
SF2	issuername	Issuer Name	The name of the security issuer.
SF2	ownername	Owner Name (Insider / Investor)	The name of the owner.
SF2	officertitle	Officer Title	Is the owner is an officer of the company the officer's title is provided.
SF2	isdirector	Is Director?	Is the owner a Board Director? [Y]es or [N]o.
SF2	isofficer	Is Officer?	Is the owner an officer of the company? [Y]es or [N]o.
SF2	istenpercentowner	Is Ten Percent Owner?	Does the owner hold ten percent or more of the class of security? [Y]es or [N]o.
SF2	transactiondate	Transaction Date	If there has been a transaction; the date of the transaction is provided here.
SF2	securityadcode	Security Acquired/Disposed Code	[D] Derivative; No Transaction [DA] Derivative Acquisition [DD] Derivative Disposition [N] Non-Derivative; No Transaction [NA] Non-Derivative Acquisition [ND] Non-Derivative Disposition
SF2	transactioncode	Transaction Code	The available [Transaction Codes] [Transaction Categories] Descriptions are as follows: [P] [General] Open market or private purchase of non-derivative or derivative security [S] [General] Open market or private sale of non-derivative or derivative security [V] [General] Transaction voluntarily reported earlier than required [A] [Rule 16b-3] Grant; award or other acquisition pursuant to Rule 16b-3(d) [D] [Rule 16b-3] Disposition to the issuer of issuer equity securities pursuant to Rule 16b-3(e) [F] [Rule 16b-3] Payment of exercise price or tax liability by delivering or withholding securities [I] [Rule 16b-3] Discretionary transaction in accordance with Rule 16b-3(f) [M] [Rule 16b-3] Exercise or conversion of derivative security exempted pursuant to Rule 16b-3 [C] [Derivative Codes] Conversion of derivative security [E] [Derivative Codes] Expiration of short derivative position [H] [Derivative Codes] Expiration (or cancellation) of long derivative position with value received [O] [Derivative Codes] Exercise of out-of-the-money derivative security [X] [Derivative Codes] Exercise of in-the-money or at-the-money derivative security [G] [Other Section 16(b) Exempt] Bona fide gift [L] [Other Section 16(b) Exempt] Small acquisition under Rule 16a-6 [W] [Other Section 16(b) Exempt] Acquisition or disposition by will or the laws of descent and distribution [Z] [Other Section 16(b) Exempt] Deposit into or withdrawal from voting trust [J] [Other] Other acquisition or disposition [K] [Other] Transaction in equity swap or instrument with similar characteristics [U] [Other] Disposition pursuant to a tender of shares in a change of control transaction
SF2	sharesownedbeforetransaction	Shares Owned Before Transaction	The number of shares owned before the transaction.
SF2	transactionshares	Transaction Shares	The number of shares transacted.
SF2	sharesownedfollowingtransaction	Shares Owned Following Transaction	The number of shares owned following the transaction.
SF2	transactionpricepershare	Transaction Price per Share	The transaction price per share.
SF2	transactionvalue	Transaction Value	The value of the transaction.
SF2	securitytitle	Security Title	The title of the class of security.
SF2	directorindirect	Direct or Indirect?	Is the ownership held [D]irectly or [I]ndirectly?
SF2	natureofownership	Nature of Ownership	Where the ownership is held through an investment vehicle (trust; fund etc) the name of that investment vehicle is provided here.
SF2	dateexercisable	Date Exercisable	The date that an option is exercisable; where applicable and available.
SF2	priceexercisable	Price Exercisable	The price at which an option is exercisable; where applicable and available.
SF2	expirationdate	Expiration Date	The data at which an option expires; where applicable and available
SF2	rownum	Row Number	The record number for a particular owner and filing date; which forms part of the key for the record.
SF3	ticker	Ticker Symbol	The ticker is a unique identifier for a security in the database. Where a company is delisted and the ticker subsequently recycled for use by a different company; we utilise that ticker for the currently active company and append a number to the ticker of the delisted company. The ACTIONS table provides a record of historical ticker changes.
SF3	investorname	Institutional Investor Name	The investor name is a unique identifier for the institutional investor.
SF3	securitytype	Security Type	The available options to filter the SecurityType field are as follows: [SHR] Common Shares [FND] Fund Units [CLL] Call Options [PUT] Put Options [WNT] Warrants [DBT] Debt [PRF] Preferred Shares [UND] Unidentified Security Type
SF3	calendardate	Calendar Date	The calendar date field represents the last day of the calendar quarter.
SF3	value	Value	The total USD value of the current line item.
SF3	units	Units	The number of units in the current line item.
SF3	price	Price	The imputed price per unit of the current line item.
SF3A	calendardate	Calendar Date	The calendar date field represents the last day of the calendar quarter.
SF3A	ticker	Ticker Symbol	The ticker is a unique identifier for a security in the database. Where a company is delisted and the ticker subsequently recycled for use by a different company; we utilise that ticker for the currently active company and append a number to the ticker of the delisted company. The ACTIONS table provides a record of historical ticker changes.
SF3A	name	Issuer Name	The name of the issuer.
SF3A	shrholders	Number of Shareholders (Institutional)	The number of shareholders.
SF3A	cllholders	Number of Call holders (Institutional)	The number of call holders.
SF3A	putholders	Number of Put holders (institutional)	The number of put holders.
SF3A	wntholders	Number of Warrant holders (institutional)	The number of warrant holders.
SF3A	dbtholders	Number of Debt holders (institutional)	The number of debt holders.
SF3A	prfholders	Number of Preferred Stock holders (institutional)	The number of preferred stock holders.
SF3A	fndholders	Number of Fund holders (institutional)	The number of fund holders.
SF3A	undholders	Number of Unidentified Security type holders (institutional)	The number of unidentified security type holders.
SF3A	shrunits	Number of Share Units held (institutional)	The total number of share units held.
SF3A	cllunits	Number of Call Units held (institutional)	The total number of call units held.
SF3A	putunits	Number of Put Units held (institutional)	The total number of put units held.
SF3A	wntunits	Number of Warrant Units held (institutional)	The total number of warrant units held.
SF3A	dbtunits	Number of Debt Units held (institutional)	The total number of debt units held.
SF3A	prfunits	Number of Preferred Stock units held (institutional)	The total number of preferred stock units held.
SF3A	fndunits	Number of Fund units held (institutional)	The total number of fund units held.
SF3A	undunits	Number of Unidentified Security type units held (institutional)	The total number of unidentified security type units held.
SF3A	shrvalue	Value of Share units held (institutional)	The total value of share units held.
SF3A	cllvalue	Value of Call units held (institutional)	The total value of call units held.
SF3A	putvalue	Value of Put units held (institutional)	The total value of put units held.
SF3A	wntvalue	Value of Warrant units held (institutional)	The total value of warrant units held.
SF3A	dbtvalue	Value of Debt units held (institutional)	The total value of debt units held.
SF3A	prfvalue	Value of Preferred Stock units held (institutional)	The total value of preferred stock units held.
SF3A	fndvalue	Value of Fund units held (institutional)	The total value of fund units held.
SF3A	undvalue	Value of Unidentified Security type units held (institutional)	The total value of unidentified security type units held.
SF3A	totalvalue	Total Value of all Security types held (institutional)	The total value of all security types held.
SF3A	percentoftotal	Percentage of Total Institutional Holdings for the Quarter	The percentage that the [TotalValue] of this line item constitutes of all institutional holdings for this quarter.
SF3B	calendardate	Calendar Date	The calendar date field represents the last day of the calendar quarter.
SF3B	investorname	Institutional Investor Name	The investor name is a unique identifier for the institutional investor.
SF3B	shrholdings	Number of Distinct Share holdings (institutional)	The number of distinct share holdings held by the institution.
SF3B	cllholdings	Number of Distinct Call holdings (institutional)	The number of distinct call holdings held by the institution.
SF3B	putholdings	Number of Distinct Put holdings (institutional)	The number of distinct put holdings held by the institution.
SF3B	wntholdings	Number of Distinct Warrant holdings (institutional)	The number of distinct warrant holdings held by the institution.
SF3B	dbtholdings	Number of Distinct Debt holdings (institutional)	The number of distinct debt holdings held by the institution.
SF3B	prfholdings	Number of Distinct Preferred Stock holdings (institutional)	The number of distinct preferred stock holdings held by the institution.
SF3B	fndholdings	Number of Distinct Fund holdings (institutional)	The number of distinct fund holdings held by the institution.
SF3B	undholdings	Number of Distinct Unidentified Security type holdings (institutional)	The number of distinct unidentified security types held by the institution.
SF3B	shrunits	Number of Share Units held (institutional)	The total number of share units held.
SF3B	cllunits	Number of Call Units held (institutional)	The total number of call units held.
SF3B	putunits	Number of Put Units held (institutional)	The total number of put units held.
SF3B	wntunits	Number of Warrant Units held (institutional)	The total number of warrant units held.
SF3B	dbtunits	Number of Debt Units held (institutional)	The total number of debt units held.
SF3B	prfunits	Number of Preferred Stock units held (institutional)	The total number of preferred stock units held.
SF3B	fndunits	Number of Fund units held (institutional)	The total number of preferred stock units held.
SF3B	undunits	Number of Unidentified Security type units held (institutional)	The total number of unidentified security type units held.
SF3B	shrvalue	Value of Share units held (institutional)	The total value of share units held.
SF3B	cllvalue	Value of Call units held (institutional)	The total value of call units held.
SF3B	putvalue	Value of Put units held (institutional)	The total value of put units held.
SF3B	wntvalue	Value of Warrant units held (institutional)	The total value of warrant units held.
SF3B	dbtvalue	Value of Debt units held (institutional)	The total value of debt units held.
SF3B	prfvalue	Value of Preferred Stock units held (institutional)	The total value of preferred stock units held.
SF3B	fndvalue	Value of Fund units held (institutional)	The total value of fund units held.
SF3B	undvalue	Value of Unidentified Security type units held (institutional)	The total value of unidentified security type units held.
SF3B	totalvalue	Total Value of all Security types held (institutional)	The total value of unidentified security type units held.
SF3B	percentoftotal	Percentage of Total Institutional Holdings for the Quarter	The percentage that the [TotalValue] of this line item constitutes of all institutional holdings for this quarter.
SFP	ticker	Ticker Symbol	The ticker is a unique identifier for a security in the database. Where a company is delisted and the ticker subsequently recycled for use by a different company; we utilise that ticker for the currently active company and append a number to the ticker of the delisted company. The ACTIONS table provides a record of historical ticker changes.
SFP	date	Price Date	The trade date of the price observations.
SFP	open	Open Price - Split Adjusted	The official exchange opening price; adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends. Not adjusted for cash dividends or spinoffs.
SFP	high	High Price - Split Adjusted	The high share price; adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends. Not adjusted for cash dividends or spinoffs.
SFP	low	Low Price - Split Adjusted	The low share price; adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends. Not adjusted for cash dividends or spinoffs.
SFP	close	Close Price - Split Adjusted	The official exchange close price; adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends. Not adjusted for cash dividends or spinoffs.
SFP	volume	Volume - Split Adjusted	The daily traded volume across all exchanges; adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends. Not adjusted for cash dividends or spinoffs. Includes opening and closing cross volume if applicable.
SFP	closeadj	Close Price - Adjusted for Splits Dividends and Spinoffs	The official exchange close price; adjusted for stock splits; stock dividends; cash dividends and spinoffs.
SFP	closeunadj	Close Price - Unadjusted	The official exchange close price; not adjusted for stock splits; stock dividends; cash dividends or spinoffs.
SFP	lastupdated	Last Updated Date	The last date at which this line item was updated; typically used to filter data to be retrieved for syncing to local records.
ACTIONS	date	Date	The date of the corporate action.
ACTIONS	action	Action	The available actions in this field are outlined in the INDICATORS table where the table field equals ACTIONTYPES.
ACTIONS	ticker	Ticker Symbol	The ticker is a unique identifier for a security in the database. Where a company is delisted and the ticker subsequently recycled for use by a different company; we utilise that ticker for the currently active company and append a number to the ticker of the delisted company. The ACTIONS table provides a record of historical ticker changes.
ACTIONS	name	Issuer Name	The name of the issuer.
ACTIONS	value	Value	The available values in this field are outlined in the INDICATORS table where the table field equals ACTIONTYPES.
ACTIONS	contraticker	Contra Ticker Symbol	The contra ticker associated with the action; if applicable.
ACTIONS	contraname	Contra Issuer Name	The name of the contra issuer associated with the contra ticker.
ACTIONTYPES	acquisitionby	Acquisition By	Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides details of an acquisition transaction. The ticker field represents the ticker of the acquired company. The contraticker field represents the ticker of the acquiring company. The value field represents the final market cap of the acquired company. The date field represents the last trade date of the acquired company.
ACTIONTYPES	acquisitionof	Acquisition Of	Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides details of an acquisition transaction. The ticker field represents the ticker of the acquiring company. The contraticker field represents the ticker of the acquired company. The value field represents the final market cap of the acquired company. The date field represents the last trade date of the acquired company.
ACTIONTYPES	bankruptcyliquidation	Bankruptcy and/or Liquidation	Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides details of a bankruptcy/liquidation transaction.  The value field represents the final market cap of the bankrupt/liquidated company.  The date field represents the last trade date of the bankrupt/liquidated company.
ACTIONTYPES	delisted	Delisted	Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides details of a delisting transaction. The value field represents the final market cap of the security provided that it is the primary common stock that is covered in the fundamentals and daily metrics tables.  The date field represents the last trade date of the delisted company.
ACTIONTYPES	dividend	Cash Dividend	Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides details of a cash dividend distribution. The value field represents the cash dividend as adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends. The date field represents the ex-dividend date.
ACTIONTYPES	initiated	Coverage Initiated	Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides details of the initiation of coverage in our price datasets. The date field represents the date that coverage commenced in our price datasets for securities that were already listed prior to this date.
ACTIONTYPES	listed	Newly Listed	Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides details of new listings. The value field represents the initial market cap of the security provided that it is the primary common stock that is covered in the fundamentals and daily metrics tables. The date field represents the date that the company listed for trading.
ACTIONTYPES	mergerfrom	Merger From	Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides details of merger transactions. The ticker field represents the ticker of the non-surviving company. The contraticker field represents the ticker of the surviving company. The value field represents the final market cap of the non-surviving company. The date field represents the last trade date of the non-surviving company.
ACTIONTYPES	mergerto	Merger To	Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides details of merger transactions. The ticker field represents the ticker of the surviving company. The contraticker field represents the ticker of the non-surviving company. The value field represents the final market cap of the non-surviving company. The date field represents the last trade date of the non-surviving company.
ACTIONTYPES	regulatorydelisting	Regulatory Delisting	Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides details of securities delisted for exchange or regulatory reasons. The value field represents the final market cap of the security provided that it is the primary common stock that is covered in the fundamentals and daily metrics tables. The date field represents the last trade date of the delisted company.
ACTIONTYPES	relation	Relation	Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides linkage between multiple securities issued by the same issuer. The ticker field represents what we consider to be the primary security from the issuer. The contraticker field represents the ticker that is related to the primary ticker.
ACTIONTYPES	spinoff	Spinoff Ratio	"Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides details of spinoff transactions.	The ticker field represents the parent company that has spunoff another company. The contraticker field represents the company that has been spunoff. The value field represents the number of shares of the spunoff company that are issued for each share of the parent company. The date field represents the date of the spinoff transaction."
ACTIONTYPES	spinoffdividend	Spinoff Dividend	Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides details of spinoff transactions. The ticker field represents the parent company that has spunoff another company. The contraticker field represents the company that has been spunoff. The value field represents the dollar value of shares of the spunoff company that are issued for each share of the parent company. The date field represents the date of the spinoff transaction.
ACTIONTYPES	split	Stock Split or Stock Dividend	Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides details of stock split or stock dividend transactions. The value field represents the number of shares that will be held after the transaction is effective for each share held prior to the transaction being effective. The date field represents the effective date of the transaction.
ACTIONTYPES	adrratiosplit	ADR Ratio Split	Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides a split applied to the ADR ratio as represented by the sharefactor indicator.
ACTIONTYPES	spunofffrom	Spunoff From	Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides details of spinoff transactions. The ticker field represents the company that has been spunoff from the parent company. The contraticker field represents the parent company. The value field represents the number of shares of the spunoff company that are issued for each share of the parent company. The date field represents the date of the spinoff transaction.
ACTIONTYPES	tickerchangefrom	Ticker Change From	Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides details of ticker change transactions. Must be viewed in conjunction with the tickerchangeto action. The ticker field represents the current ticker in the datasets which is not necessarily the ticker that has been changed to as of this date. The contraticker field represents the ticker that has been changed from as of this date. The tickerchangeto action represents the ticker that was changed to as of the date in the date field. The date field represents the effective date of the ticker change.
ACTIONTYPES	tickerchangeto	Ticker Change To	Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides details of ticker change transactions. Must be viewed in conjunction with the tickerchangefrom action. The ticker field represents the current ticker in the datasets which is not necessarily the ticker that has been changed to as of this date. The contraticker field represents the ticker that has been changed to as of this date. The tickerchangefrom action represents the ticker that was changed from as of the date in the date field. The date field represents the effective date of the ticker change.
ACTIONTYPES	voluntarydelisting	Voluntary Delisting	"Description of action types in the ACTIONS table. Provides details of securities that have voluntarily delisted. The value field represents the final market cap of the security provided that it is the primary common stock that is covered in the fundamentals and daily metrics tables. The date field represents the last trade date of the delisted company.	"
EVENTCODES	81	Other Events	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	91	Financial Statements and Exhibits	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
DAILY	ticker	Ticker Symbol	The ticker is a unique identifier for a security in the database. Where a company is delisted and the ticker subsequently recycled for use by a different company; we utilise that ticker for the currently active company and append a number to the ticker of the delisted company. The ACTIONS table provides a record of historical ticker changes.
DAILY	date	Price Date	The trade date of the price observations used in determining [MarketCap]; [PE]; [PS] etc.
DAILY	lastupdated	Last Updated Date	The last date at which this line item was updated; typically used to filter date to be retrieved for syncing to local records.
DAILY	ev	Enterprise Value - Daily	Enterprise value is a measure of the value of a business as a whole; calculated as [MarketCap] plus [DebtUSD] minus [CashnEqUSD]. [MarketCap] is calculated by us; and the remaining figures are sourced from the most recent SEC form 10 filings.
DAILY	evebit	Enterprise Value over EBIT - Daily	Measures the ratio between [EV] and [EBITUSD]. EBITUSD is derived from the most recent SEC form 10 filings.
DAILY	evebitda	Enterprise Value over EBITDA - Daily	Measures the ratio between [EV] and [EBITDAUSD]. EBITDAUSD is derived from the most recent SEC form 10 filings.
DAILY	marketcap	Market Capitalization - Daily	Represents the product of [SharesBas]; [Price] and [ShareFactor]. [SharesBas] is sourced from the most recent SEC form 10 filing.
DAILY	pb	Price to Book Value - Daily	Measures the ratio between [MarketCap] and [EquityUSD]. [EquityUSD] is sourced from the most recent SEC form 10 filing.
DAILY	pe	Price Earnings (Damodaran Method) - Daily	Measures the ratio between [MarketCap] and [NetIncCmnUSD]. [NetIncCmnUSD] is sourced from the most recent SEC form 10 filings.
DAILY	ps	Price Sales (Damodaran Method) - Daily	Measures the ratio between [MarketCap] and [RevenueUSD]. [RevenueUSD] is sourced from the most recent SEC form 10 filings.
EVENTCODES	11	Entry into a Material Definitive Agreement	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	12	Termination of a Material Definitive Agreement	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	13	Bankruptcy or Receivership	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	14	Mine Safety - Reporting of Shutdowns and Patterns of Violations	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	15	Receipt of an Attorney's Written Notice Pursuant to 17 CFR 205.3(d) 	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	21	Completion of Acquisition or Disposition of Assets	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	22	Results of Operations and Financial Condition	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	23	Creation of a Direct Financial Obligation or an Obligation under an Off-Balance Sheet Arrangement of a Registrant	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	24	Triggering Events That Accelerate or Increase a Direct Financial Obligation or an Obligation under an Off-Balance Sheet Arrangement	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	25	Cost Associated with Exit or Disposal Activities	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	26	Material Impairments	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	31	Notice of Delisting or Failure to Satisfy a Continued Listing Rule or Standard; Transfer of Listing	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	32	Unregistered Sales of Equity Securities	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	33	Material Modifications to Rights of Security Holders	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	34	Schedule 13G Filing	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	35	Schedule 13D Filing	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	36	Notice under Rule 12b25 of inability to timely file all or part of a Form 10-K or 10-Q	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	40	Changes in Registrant's Certifying Accountant	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	41	Changes in Registrant's Certifying Accountant	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	42	Non-Reliance on Previously Issued Financial Statements or a Related Audit Report or Completed Interim Review	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	51	Changes in Control of Registrant	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	52	Departure of Directors or Certain Officers; Election of Directors; Appointment of Certain Officers: Compensatory Arrangements of Certain Officers	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	53	Amendments to Articles of Incorporation or Bylaws; and/or Change in Fiscal Year	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	54	Temporary Suspension of Trading Under Registrant's Employee Benefit Plans	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	55	Amendments to the Registrant's Code of Ethics; or Waiver of a Provision of the Code of Ethics	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	56	Change in Shell Company Status	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	57	Submission of Matters to a Vote of Security Holders	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	58	Shareholder Nominations Pursuant to Exchange Act Rule 14a-11	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	61	ABS Informational and Computational Material	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	62	Change of Servicer or Trustee	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	63	Change in Credit Enhancement or Other External Support	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	64	Failure to Make a Required Distribution	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	65	Securities Act Updating Disclosure	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	71	Regulation FD Disclosure	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTCODES	37	Tender Offer Statement under Section 14(d)(1) or 13(e)(1) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934	EventCode to Title mapping for EVENTS table.
EVENTS	date	Filing Date	The date of the form 8 SEC filing.
EVENTS	ticker	Ticker Symbol	The ticker is a unique identifier for a security in the database. Where a company is delisted and the ticker subsequently recycled for use by a different company; we utilise that ticker for the currently active company and append a number to the ticker of the delisted company. The ACTIONS table provides a record of historical ticker changes.
EVENTS	eventcodes	Material Corporate Events	Each type of event is assigned a 2-digit numeric code which are described in this INDICATORS table where the table field equals EVENTCODES.
INDICATORS	table	Table	"The database table which the ticker is featured in. Examples are: SF1 or SEP.	"
INDICATORS	indicator	Indicator Code	
INDICATORS	isfilter	Is Filter?	
INDICATORS	isprimarykey	Is Primary Key?	
INDICATORS	title	Indicator Title	
INDICATORS	description	Indicator Description	
INDICATORS	unittype	Indicator Unit Type	
METRICS	ticker	Ticker Symbol	The ticker is a unique identifier for a security in the database. Where a company is delisted and the ticker subsequently recycled for use by a different company; we utilise that ticker for the currently active company and append a number to the ticker of the delisted company. The ACTIONS table provides a record of historical ticker changes.
METRICS	date	Price Date	The trade date of the most recent price and volume available.
METRICS	lastupdated	Last Updated Date	Last updated date represents the last date that this table entry was updated; which is useful to users when updating their local records.
METRICS	beta1y	Beta - 1 Year Daily	The beta of the stock over 1 year relative to the market calculated using daily adjusted closing price of the stock (as adjusted for stock splits; dividends and spinoffs) relative to total returns of the market as represented by the adjusted closing prices of the SPY S&P500 ETF. Recalculated and updated on a weekly basis.
METRICS	beta5y	Beta - 5 Year Monthly	The beta of the stock over 5 years relative to the market calculated using monthly adjusted closing price of the stock (as adjusted for stock splits; dividends and spinoffs) relative to total returns of the market as represented by the adjusted closing prices of the SPY S&P500 ETF. Recalculated and updated on a weekly basis.
METRICS	dividendyieldforward	Dividend Yield - Forward	The forward dividend yield; calculated by annualising the last regular cash dividend payment; dividing by the stock price and multiplying by 100.
METRICS	dividendyieldtrailing	Dividend Yield - Trailing	The trailing dividend yield; calculated by summing regular and special cash dividend payments in the last year; dividing by the stock price and multiplying by 100.
METRICS	high52w	High Price - 52 Week	The highest price over the last 52 weeks as adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends; but not cash dividends or spinoffs.
METRICS	high5y	High Price - 5 Year	The highest price over the last 5 years as adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends; but not cash dividends or spinoffs.
METRICS	low52w	Low Price - 52 Week	The lowest price over the last 52 weeks as adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends; but not cash dividends or spinoffs.
METRICS	low5y	Low Price - 5 Year	The lowest price over the last 5 years weeks as adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends; but not cash dividends or spinoffs.
METRICS	ma200d	Price Moving Average - 200 Day	The 200 day moving average closing price as adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends; but not cash dividends or spinoffs. Not available if the stock has been trading less than 200 days.
METRICS	ma200w	Price Moving Average - 200 Week	The 200 week moving average closing price as adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends; but not cash dividends or spinoffs. Not available if the stock has been trading less than 200 weeks.
METRICS	ma50d	Price Moving Average - 50 Day	The 50 day moving average closing price as adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends; but not cash dividends or spinoffs. Not available if the stock has been trading less than 50 days.
METRICS	ma50w	Price Moving Average - 50 Week	The 50 week moving average closing price as adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends; but not cash dividends or spinoffs. Not available if the stock has been trading less than 50 weeks.
METRICS	price	Price	The closing stock price on the date.
METRICS	return1y	Total Return - 1 Year	The total return over 1 year calculated using the closing price as adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends; but not cash dividends or spinoffs. Not available if the stock has been trading for less than 1 year.
METRICS	return5y	Total Return - 5 Year	The total return over 5 years calculated using the closing price as adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends; but not cash dividends or spinoffs. Not available if the stock has been trading for less than 5 years.
METRICS	returnytd	Total Return - Year to Date	The total return for the year to date calculated using the closing price as adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends; but not cash dividends or spinoffs.
METRICS	volume	Volume	The daily traded volume across all exchanges; adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends. Not adjusted for cash dividends or spinoffs. Includes opening and closing cross volumes if applicable.
METRICS	volumeavg1m	Volume Average - 1 Month	The daily average traded volume over 1 month across all exchanges; adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends. Not adjusted for cash dividends or spinoffs. Includes opening and closing cross volumes if applicable.
METRICS	volumeavg3m	Volume Average - 3 Month	The daily average traded volume over 3 months across all exchanges; adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends. Not adjusted for cash dividends or spinoffs. Includes opening and closing cross volumes if applicable.
TICKERS	table	Table	The database table which the ticker is featured in. Examples are: SF1 or SEP.
SEP	ticker	Ticker Symbol	The ticker is a unique identifier for a security in the database. Where a company is delisted and the ticker subsequently recycled for use by a different company; we utilise that ticker for the currently active company and append a number to the ticker of the delisted company. The ACTIONS table provides a record of historical ticker changes.
SEP	date	Price Date	The trade date of the price observations.
SEP	open	Open Price - Split Adjusted	The official exchange opening price; adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends. Not adjusted for cash dividends or spinoffs.
SEP	high	High Price - Split Adjusted	The high share price; adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends. Not adjusted for cash dividends or spinoffs.
SEP	low	Low Price - Split Adjusted	The low share price; adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends. Not adjusted for cash dividends or spinoffs.
SEP	close	Close Price - Split Adjusted	The official exchange close price; adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends. Not adjusted for cash dividends or spinoffs.
SEP	volume	Volume - Split Adjusted	The daily traded volume across all exchanges; adjusted for stock splits and stock dividends. Not adjusted for cash dividends or spinoffs. Includes opening and closing cross volumes if applicable.
SEP	closeadj	Close Price - Adjusted for Splits Dividends and Spinoffs	The official exchange close price; adjusted for stock splits; stock dividends; cash dividends and spinoffs.
SEP	closeunadj	Close Price - Unadjusted	The official exchange close price; not adjusted for stock splits; stock dividends; cash dividends or spinoffs.
SEP	lastupdated	Last Updated Date	The last date at which this line item was updated; typically used to filter data to be retrieved for syncing to local records.
SP500	date	Date	The action date.
SP500	action	Action	"The available actions in this database are: current; added; removed and historical.	"
SP500	ticker	Ticker Symbol	The ticker is a unique identifier for a security in the database. Where a company is delisted and the ticker subsequently recycled for use by a different company; we utilise that ticker for the currently active company and append a number to the ticker of the delisted company. The ACTIONS table provides a record of historical ticker changes.
SP500	name	Issuer Name	The name of the issuer.
SP500	contraticker	Contra Ticker Symbol	The contra ticker is the opposing ticker entry. It represents the ticker that has been removed where the action=added; and the ticker that has been added where the action=removed.
SP500	contraname	Contra Issuer Name	The name of the contra issuer.
SP500	note	Notes	Placeholder for notes and additional information regarding additions to and removals from the S&P500.
TABLE-DESCRIPTIONS	SF1	Core US Fundamentals Table (SF1)	"The primary US fundamentals table that contains income statement; balance sheet; cash flow statement, and derived and price-based metrics. Observations are provided quarterly; annually; and for trailing twelve month periods where available. Multiple dimensions are provided to view the data before and after the impact of restatements. The data are originally curated from SEC filings via forms 10; 20; 40; S-1; S-4; F-1; F-40; and 6-K."
TABLE-DESCRIPTIONS	SF2	Core US Insiders Table (SF2)	The SHARADAR/SF2 table contains insider transactions and holdings from SEC filings via form 3; 4; and 5. These filings must be made within 2 business days of any transaction occurring. Find out more about the SEC filing requirements here: https://www.sec.gov/files/forms-3-4-5.pdf.
TABLE-DESCRIPTIONS	SF3	Sharadar US Institutional Investors Table (SF3)	The SHARADAR/SF3 table contains institutional investor portfolio holdings disclosed via SEC form 13F filings. These filings are made quarterly up to 45 days after the end of the quarter. Find out more about the SEC filing requirements here: https://www.sec.gov/pdf/form13f.pdf.
TABLE-DESCRIPTIONS	SF3A	Sharadar US Institutional Investors Summary By Ticker Table (SF3A)	The SHARADAR/SF3A table summarises the institutional investor table (SF3) by ticker.
TABLE-DESCRIPTIONS	SF3B	Sharadar US Institutional Investors Summary By Investor Table (SF3B)	The SHARADAR/SF3B table summarises the institutional investor table (SF3) by investor.
TABLE-DESCRIPTIONS	SEP	Sharadar Equity Prices Table (SEP)	The SHARADAR/SEP table provides end-of-day (EOD) prices for listed equities; including common stock; warrants and preferred stock. Data are provided (1) unadjusted (2) adjusted for stock splits (3) adjusted for stock splits; cash dividends; and spinoffs.
TABLE-DESCRIPTIONS	SFP	Sharadar Fund Prices Table (SFP)	The SHARADAR/SFP table provides end-of-day (EOD) prices for listed equities; including common stock; warrants and preferred stock. Data are provided (1) unadjusted (2) adjusted for stock splits (3) adjusted for stock splits; cash dividends; and spinoffs.
TABLE-DESCRIPTIONS	TICKERS	Sharadar Tickers And Metadata Table (TICKERS)	The SHARADAR/TICKERS table provides rich metadata for tickers in the SF1; SEP; and SFP tables. In addition it provides metadata for investors in the SF3/SF3B tables. 
TABLE-DESCRIPTIONS	INDICATORS	Sharadar Indicator Descriptions Table (INDICATORS)	The SHARADAR/INDICATORS table provides descriptions of the indicators available in the Sharadar tables.
TABLE-DESCRIPTIONS	DAILY	Sharadar Daily Fundamental Metrics Table (DAILY)	The SHARADAR/DAILY table provides price-based fundamentals metrics with daily resolution.
TABLE-DESCRIPTIONS	SP500	Sharadar S&P500 Current And Historical Constituents Table (SP500)	The SHARADAR/DAILY table provides current S&P500 constituents; as well as historical changes and historical constituents.
TABLE-DESCRIPTIONS	ACTIONS	Sharadar Corporate Actions Table (ACTIONS)	The SHARADAR/ACTIONS table provides rich corporate actions history that includes cash dividends; ticker changes; spinoffs; M&A; bankruptcies and other delistings.
TABLE-DESCRIPTIONS	EVENTS	Sharadar Material Corporate Events Table (EVENTS)	The SHARADAR/EVENTS table provides material corporate events as reported to the SEC via form 8-K. Find out more about the SEC filing requirements here: https://www.sec.gov/files/form8-k.pdf.
TABLE-DESCRIPTIONS	METRICS	Sharadar Price Based Metrics Table (METRICS)	The SHARADAR/METRICS table provides price-based metrics such as beta; dividend yield; moving averages; high price; low price; and average volume.
TICKERS	permaticker	Permanent Ticker Symbol	The permaticker is a unique and unchanging identifier for an issuer in the dataset which we as the data provider issue. This field is not included in other tables in order to maximise data scalability in those tables.
TICKERS	ticker	Ticker Symbol	The ticker is a unique identifier for a security in the database. Where a company is delisted and the ticker subsequently recycled for use by a different company; we utilise that ticker for the currently active company and append a number to the ticker of the delisted company. The ACTIONS table provides a record of historical ticker changes.
TICKERS	name	Issuer Name	The name of the security issuer.
TICKERS	exchange	Stock Exchange	The exchange on which the security's primary listing is held. Examples are: 
TICKERS	isdelisted	Is Delisted?	Is the security delisted? [Y]es or [N]o.
TICKERS	category	Issuer Category	The category of the issuer: Domestic; Canadian or ADR. This field is based on the filing category with the SEC. Domestic firms file form 10; ADRs file form 20 and Canadian firms file form 40.
TICKERS	cusips	CUSIPs	A security identifier. Space delimited in the event of multiple identifiers.
TICKERS	siccode	Standard Industrial Classification (SIC) Code	The Standard Industrial Classification (SIC) is a system for classifying industries by a four-digit code; as sourced from SEC filings. More on the SIC system here: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_Industrial_Classification 
TICKERS	sicsector	SIC Sector	The SIC sector is based on the SIC code and the division tabled here: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Standard_Industrial_Classification 
TICKERS	sicindustry	SIC Industry	The SIC industry is based on the SIC code and the industry tabled here: https://www.sec.gov/info/edgar/siccodes.htm
TICKERS	famasector	Fama Sector	This field was originally configured as a placeholder for the sector value in the Fama-French SIC to industry and sector mapping. As it turns out there is no sector in this mapping. As such we are open to suggestions for other values you would rather see here email connect@sharadar.com with suggestions.
TICKERS	famaindustry	Fama Industry	Industry classifications based on the SIC code and classifications by Fama and French here: http://mba.tuck.dartmouth.edu/pages/faculty/ken.french/Data_Library/det_48_ind_port.html
TICKERS	sector	Sector	A sector classification based on SIC codes in a format which approximates to GICS.
TICKERS	industry	Industry	An industry classification based on SIC codes in a format which approximates to GICS.
TICKERS	scalemarketcap	Company Scale - Market Cap	This field is experimental and subject to change. It categorises the company according to it's maximum observed market cap as follows: 1 - Nano <$50m; 2 - Micro < $300m; 3 - Small < $2bn; 4 - Mid <$10bn; 5 - Large < $200bn; 6 - Mega >= $200bn
TICKERS	scalerevenue	Company Scale - Revenue	This field is experimental and subject to change. It categorises the company according to it's maximum observed annual revenue as follows: 1 - Nano <$50m; 2 - Micro < $300m; 3 - Small < $2bn; 4 - Mid <$10bn; 5 - Large < $200bn; 6 - Mega >= $200bn
TICKERS	relatedtickers	Related Tickers	Where related tickers have been identified this field is populated. Related tickers can include the prior ticker before a ticker change; and it includes tickers for alternative share classes.
TICKERS	currency	Currency	The company functional reporting currency for the SF1 Fundamentals table or the currency for EOD prices in SEP and SFP.
TICKERS	location	Location	The company location as registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission.
TICKERS	lastupdated	Last Updated Date	Last Updated represents the last date that this database entry was updated; which is useful to users when updating their local records.
TICKERS	firstadded	First Added Date	The date that the ticker was first added to coverage in the dataset.
TICKERS	firstpricedate	First Price Date	The date of the first price observation for a given ticker. Can be used as a proxy for IPO date. Minimum value of 1986-01-01 for IPO's that occurred prior to this date. Note: this does not necessarily represent the first price date available in our datasets since our end of day price history currently starts in December 1998.
TICKERS	lastpricedate	Last Price Date	The most recent price observation available.
TICKERS	firstquarter	First Quarter	The first financial quarter available in the dataset.
TICKERS	lastquarter	Last Quarter	The last financial quarter available in the dataset.
TICKERS	secfilings	SEC Filings URL	The URL pointing to the SEC filings which also contains the Central Index Key (CIK).
TICKERS	companysite	Company Website URL	The URL pointing to the company website.
